Contact

jase.ly@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/jason-ly-msn-rn-pccn-cmsrn-03bb463b (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Healthcare

Nursing

Medical Terminology

Languages

Khmer

English

Certifications

Certified Medical-Surgical Registered Nurse

Basic Life Support for Healthcare Providers

Advanced Cardiac Life Support

Jason Ly, MSN, RN, PCCN, CMSRN

Assistant Patient Care Manager - Float Pool at Stanford Health Care San Francisco Bay Area

Summary

I am a nurse leader that is passionate about health care and its intersection with technology. My interests also include working with underserved communities, social justice, and transformational leadership. As a leader, I strive to provide the latest evidence-based practices to the bedside through means of engaging with research, educating colleagues and patients, and acting as a champion of systems-level changes.

Experience

Stanford Health Care

4 years 5 months

Assistant Patient Care Manager - Float Pool & Safety Observation Specialists

March 2020 - Present (4 months)

Assistant Patient Care Manager - C3 Intermediate ICU/General Medicine

August 2018 - March 2020 (1 year 8 months)

San Francisco Bay Area

I assist with managing the day-to-day operations of a 26-bed, inpatient unit that consists of general medicine and telemetry patients. Along with the Patient Care Manager (PCM), this includes oversight of approximately 60 nursing staff, nursing assistants, and unit secretaries. My administrative tasks include hiring and scheduling of staff, maintenance of staff timecards, conducting employee performance evaluations, quality & safety patient care audits, following up with all employee and patient grievances, and lead special projects as delegated by the PCM. I also function as Charge Nurse on the night shift and serve as a liaison between staff and other nursing leadership.

Clinical Nurse II - Float Pool February 2016 - August 2018 (2 years 7 months)

San Francisco Bay Area

On a shift-to-shift basis, I help fill the needs of the hospital by floating to 19 different nursing units. I assist in coordinating and providing care for acutely ill adults on intermediate ICU/telemetry, oncology, BMT, and medical/surgical units. I am trained to function as Charge/Resource RN for patient overflow and holding areas, such as PACU and endoscopy. I also serve as chair-elect for the Float Pool Shared Leadership Council, which is our shared governance structure. I was a member of the Education Committee, which assists in making recommendations to improve patient and staff education.

University of Washington Medical Center 11 years 2 months

Unit Practice Council Co-Chair August 2014 - December 2015 (1 year 5 months)

Greater Seattle Area

Chosen to be Co-Chair for the nursing Unit Practice Council and helped to take meeting minutes, plan agenda items for meetings, facilitate civic engagement outside of the workplace, and engage in incorporating evidence-based practice into nursing care.

- -Participated in Seattle Nursing Research Consortium by co-authoring a poster project entitled, "Examining the Culture of Civility in One Magnet-Designated Academic Hospital: A Quality Improvement Project."
- -Developed educational infection control cards for nurses to wear to enhance infection control practices.
- -Provided education materials for charge nurses of inpatient boarding areas, including electronic telemetry education guide.

Registered Nurse 2 - Acute Care Resource Team July 2012 - December 2015 (3 years 6 months)

Greater Seattle Area

I successfully completed a New-Grad RN orientation, which consisted of orienting to four different acute care medical/surgical units over the course of a year on the RN float team. Thereafter, I expanded my orientation to include oncology units and the emergency department as well. On a shift-to-shift basis, I seek to use the latest evidence-based practice and utilize the nursing process to care for patients with complex illnesses across 13 different nursing units, which include: medical/surgical telemetry units, hematology/oncology and bone marrow transplant units, inpatient psych, inpatient rehab, and the emergency department. If needed, I also am able to assist in opening an inpatient auxiliary unit for patient overflow and can function as a Charge RN.

I also served as the co-chair on the Unit Practice Council and was a Magnet and Bedside Report Champion.

Nurse Technician/Patient Care Technician October 2007 - June 2012 (4 years 9 months)

Greater Seattle Area

I floated through various units within the medical center depending on the needs for that workday; therefore I am required to have knowledge of a wide range of medical specialties and medical terminology. I aided nursing staff by monitoring patient vital signs, electronically charting patient data, assisting with activities of daily living for patients, as well as answering patient call lights. I was also trained as a constant observer/suicide prevention monitor for critical patients. Other responsibilities include patient transport and lab courier services. As a nurse technician, I also performed nursing skills with the supervision of a licensed RN. These skills included: administering oral medications, subcutaneous medication injections, intravenous medication infusions, Foley catheter insertions, and wound care.

Student Assistant November 2004 - October 2007 (3 years) Seattle, WA

As a Student Assistant for the Volunteer Service League, I was cross-trained to provide operations of sales in the gift shop, the espresso bars, and the tea room. I received phone orders, which allowed for accurate and prompt communication services. I also assisted with the maintenance of inventory of stock. Knowledge and efficiency in hospital standards and procedures in all locations were vital for operation and contributed to a pleasant environment for the staff, patients, and guests of the hospital.

University of Washington Graduate and Professional Student Senate Office Manager

October 2007 - June 2008 (9 months)

Greater Seattle Area

As an office manager for the Graduate Professional Student Senate, I greeted visitors and guests at the front desk and by answering questions about University services and programs. I assisted professional and graduate students with logistical problems, and supported the four Senate officers as necessary. Other responsibilities included: coordinating meetings between officers and University administrators, maintaining office equipment and supplies, answering phones, delivering messages, and recording meeting minutes.

ASUW | Associated Students of the University of Washington Administrative Assistant to the Board of Directors September 2006 - June 2007 (10 months)

Greater Seattle Area

As an Administrative Assistant to the Board of Directors for the Association Students of the University of Washington, I attended weekly Board meetings, as well as the Judicial, Special Appropriations, and Finance and Budget committee meetings. I prepared agendas and recorded/edited meeting minutes for record keeping. I was responsible for scheduling meetings, photocopying, and other special projects as delegated by the Board members. Through the aforementioned, I was able to exercise initiative, ingenuity and sound judgment in administrative and clerical duties. My organizational and interpersonal skills have greatly developed from working with the twelve Board members and their constituencies. For my service, I was awarded as the 2007 Staff Member of the Year.

Education

California State University, Fullerton

Master of Science in Nursing - MSN, Leadership · (2017 - 2020)

University of Washington
Bachelor of Science in Nursing - BSN, Nursing · (2010 - 2012)

University of Washington

Bachelor of Arts - BA, American Ethnic Studies, Public Health & Community Medicine · (2004 - 2008)